Nancy Hale Papers, 1908-1989
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
A12 A New England Girlhood. Boston & Toronto: Little, Brown, 1958. London: Gollancz, 1958. Contents: "The Readville Stars," "The Empress's Ring," "Charlotte Russe," "Pierce's," "Cab-Taxi," "The Fair," "Copley Plaza," "The Secret Secret," "The First One," and "Coming Out" first appeared in The New Yorker. "Odd Fellows Hall" first appeared in Scribner's Magazine. "The Year I Had the Colds" was not previously published. N.B. The chapters are numbered and not titled. Chapters 2, 4, 5, 11, 12, 16, 18, 19 and 21 still require identification by title.
A13 The Pattern of Perfection. Boston & Toronto: Little, Brown, 1960. London: Macmillan, 1961. Contents: "Entrance into Life," "A Summer's Long Dream," "A Haunting," "The Pattern of Perfection," "A Curious Lapse," "The King of Fancy's Daughter," "A New Place," "Outside," "Flotsam," "No Other Gods," "Rich People"--all published first in The New Yorker. "A Slow Boat to China" first appeared in The Virginia Quarterly Review. "In a Penthouse" was not previously published.
A14 The Life in the Studio. Boston & Toronto: Little, Brown, 1969. Contents: "What Haunts Thee in Fond Shapes," "Eyes and No Eyes, or, The Art of Seeing," "My Mother's Solitudes," "The Girl with the Goat-Cart," "Mrs. Harcourt's Mare," "There Is a Host Approaching Nigh," "Joyous Gard," "Inheriting a Garden," "The World, the Flesh, and the Devil," "A Good Light," "The Other Side," and "An Arrangement in Parents" were all published first in The New Yorker. "The Black Cape" first appeared as "My Mother's Clothes" in Ladies Home Journal. "Journeys" appeared originally in The Virginia Quarterly Review. "Grape Jelly" was not previously published.
3. Children's Literature:
A15 The Night of the Hurricane. New York: Coward, McCann & Geoghegan, 1978.
A16 Birds in the House. Charlottesville, VA: Learning Center, 1985.
A17 Those Raccoons. Charlottesville, VA: Learning Center, 1985.
A18 Wags. Charlottesville, VA: Learning Center, 1985.
4. Non-Fiction:
A19 The Realities of Fiction. Boston & Toronto: Little, Brown, 1962. London: Macmillan, 1963.
A20 Mary Cassatt. Garden City, NY: Doubleday, 1975.
5. Play Productions: Performance Information
A21 The Best of Everything, Charlottesville, VA, Virginia Players, Minor Hall Theater University of Virginia, 7 May 1952.
A22 Somewhere She Dances, Charlottesville, VA, Virginia Players, Minor Hall Theater, University of Virginia, 13-16 May 1953.
6. Periodical Publication of Short Fiction:
A23 "The Aviation Country Club Takes Off." Vogue. 20 July 1929: 62, 63, 106. [Pseudonym Cornelius Vanderbilt Whitney].
A24 "The Country Club at Brookline, Sports and Games Combine in a Year-Round Season." Vogue. 17 Aug. 1929: 76, 77, 120.
A25 "Hunting at Warrenton." Vogue. 14 Sept. 1929: 102, 103, 174, 182.
A26 "Vogue's Christmas Portfolio." Vogue. 23 Nov. 1929: *, 126, 132.
A27 "The New York Winter Season." Vogue. 7 Dec. 1929: 69, 70, 71, 166, 170.
A28 "Paradise at a Price." Vogue. 21 Dec. 1929: 58, 59, 94, 96.
A29 "The Hartford Hunt at Monkton." Vogue. 18 Jan. 1930: 66, 114.
A30 "Why Guests Go Home." Vogue. 18 Jan. 1930: 68, 69, 94.
A31 "The Toiling Lily." Vogue. 1 Mar. 1930: 55, 110, 112, 114, 116. [Signed Nancy Hardin].
A32 "Foxcroft in Virginia." *. 15 Mar. 1930: 78, 79.
A33 "To-Night in New York." Vogue. 5 July 1930: 31, 33, 88. [Unsigned].
A34 "Dry-Point of a Lady." Vogue. 22 Dec. 1930: 51,74. [By Nancy Hardin].
A35 "I Take My Pen in Hand." Vogue. *: 57, 100, 108.
A36 "Under Your Frock: Moderately Priced Lingerie Seen in the Shops. Vogue*: 69, 86.
A37 "The Wolf at the Wardrobe Door: The Letter of a Young Lady of Poverty." Vogue. *: 152, 154.
A38 "Colloque Sentimentale." Scribner's Magazine. Aug. 1931: *. + + [date only]
A39 "The Girl Who Looked Like Garbo." Vanity Fair. Oct. 1931: *. + +
A40 "The Three Wise Guys." Vanity Fair. Dec. 1931: 61-*.
A41 "Club Car." The New Yorker. 26 Dec. 1931: 42-43.
A42 "The Lost Stars." Vanity Fair. 1932: *. Included in The Best Short Shorts of 1932. NewYork: Putnam's, 1932: -128.
A43 "Simple Aveu." Scribner's Magazine. May 1932: *. + +
A44 "No One My Grief Can Tell." American Mercury. Oct. 1932: *.
A45 "Love Story." O. Henry Prize Stories. 1933: *. + +
A46 "To the Invader." Modern Youth. Mar. 1933: *. Included in O. Henry Memorial Award Prize Stories of 1933. Ed. Harry Hansen. Garden City, NY: Doubleday, 1933. 61-71. Included in The Earliest Dreams [by Hale].
A47 "Wedding Present." Vanity Fair. July 1933: *. + +
A48 "White Poppies Die." Vanity Fair. Aug. 1933: *. + +
A49 "Mr. Britton." The New Yorker. 26 Aug. 1933: 17-18. Included in The Earliest Dreams [by Hale].
A50 "The Waxen Man." The American Mercury. Sept, 1933. *. + + [date only]
A51 "The Unregenerate." Vanity Fair. Jan. 1934: *. + +
A52 "George." Vanity Fair. Mar. 1934: *. + +
A53 "For Art's Sake." The New Yorker. 31 Mar. 1934: 17-19. Included in The Earliest Dreams [by Hale].
A54 "The Double House." Vanity Fair. Apr. 1934: *. Included in The Earliest Dreams [by Hale]. Included in The Best Short Stories 1935 and the Yearbook of the American Short Story. Boston: Houghton Mifflin, 1935: 210 216.
A55 "The Earliest Dreams." American Mercury. Apr. 1934: *. Included in The Earliest Dreams [by Hale].
A56 "Perfect 36." The New Yorker. 21 Apr. 1934: 76, 78-82.
A57 "Before Going Down." Scribner's Magazine. August 1934. *. + +
A58 "Midsummer." The New Yorker. 8 Sept. 1934: 28-33. Included in The Earliest Dreams [by Hale]. Included in Sometimes Magic: A Collection of Outstanding Stories for the Teenage Girl. New York: Platt & Munk, 1966. 309-320. Included in Short Stories from The New Yorker. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1940. 76-85. Included in First Love. New York: Bantam, 1948. 223-234. Included in Tales of Love and Fury. New York: Avon, 1953. 23-34.
A59 "The Great-Grandmother." The New Yorker. 7 Dec. 1935: 33-35. Included in The Earliest Dreams [by Hale]. Included in Short Stories from The New Yorker. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1940. 402-407.
A60 "The Rider Was Lost." McCall's. 1936: *. Included in The Earliest Dreams [by Hale]. Included in Love Stories. Ed. Martin Levin. New York: Quadrangle,1975. 173-186.
A61 "Love Is Not Love." Scribner's Magazine. Feb. 1936: *. + +
A62 "Mariana." Harper's Magazine. Feb. 1936: 268-274. Included in The Earliest Dreams [by Hale].
A63 "The Blue Muslin Sepulcher." Scribner's Magazine. Mar. 1936: *, 142, 143,144. Reprinted in Ladies Home Journal. * Included in The Earliest Dreams [by Hale].
A64 "To Live Alone." Harper's Magazine. Apr. 1936: 556-566.
A65 "The British Are Different." Harper's Bazaar. May 1936: *. + +
A66 "Order." Harper's Magazine. Aug. 1936: 292-301.
A67 "The First One." The New Yorker. 5 Dec. 1936: 35-37. Included in Between the Dark and the Daylight [by Hale]. Included in A New England Girlhood [by Hale].
A68 "To the North." Redbook Magazine. 1937: *. Included in O. Henry Memorial Award Prize Stories of 1937. Ed. Harry Hansen. Garden City, NY: Doubleday, 1937. 77-97.
A69 "The Carthaginian Rose." Ladies' Home Journal. Feb. 1937: 14, 15, 40, 42, 44.
A70 "Odd Fellows Hall." Scribner's Magazine. Mar. 1937: *. + + Included in A New England Girlhood [by Hale].
A71 "That Summer." The New Yorker. 6 Mar. 1937: 19-21.
A72 "Always Afternoon." Redbook Magazine. *. Included in O. Henry Memorial Award Prize Stories of 1938. Garden City: Country Life Press, 1938: 203-212.
A73 "Little Family." American Mercury. July 1939: *. + + [publication information]
A74 "Music Without Words." Collier's. 15 July 1939: 20, 21, 36-38.
A75 "That Woman." Harper's Magazine. Apr. 1940: 474-484. Included in U.S. Stories: Regional Stories from the Forty-Eight States. Eds. Martha Foley and Abraham Rothberg. New York: Hendricks House-Farrar Straus, 1949. 124-139. Included in Between the Dark and the Daylight [by Hale].
A76 "The Story of Daphne." Ladies Home Journal. Vol. 57, no. 5. May 1940: *.
A77 "Six-Fifteen." The New Yorker. 29 June 1940: 14-18. Included in Between the Dark and the Daylight [by Hale].
A78 "Separation." Redbook. July 1940: *. + +
A79 "Though It Breaks My Heart to Go." The New Yorker. 17 Aug. 1940: 47-48. Included in Between the Dark and the Daylight [by Hale].
A80 "Poor White." Mademoiselle. Oct. 1940. 130-131.
A81 "You Can't Run Away." Ladies Home Journal. Nov. 1940: *. + +
A82 "Halloween." The New Yorker. 2 Nov. 1940: 17-18. Included in Between the Dark and the Daylight [by Hale].
A83 "Between the Dark and the Daylight." The New Yorker. 16 Nov. 1940: 17-19. Included in A Time of Growing. Ed. Jean Van Leeuwen. New York: Random House, 1967. 3-12. Included in Prose for Mademoiselle. Ed. Brigid O'Reilly. Canada: Science Research Associates, 1968. 149-155. Included in Between the Dark and the Daylight [by Hale].
A84 "A Place to Hide In." The New Yorker. 14 Dec. 1940: 29-30. Included in Between the Dark and the Daylight [by Hale].
A85 "Those Are As Brothers." Mademoiselle. 1941: *. Included in Between the Dark and the Daylight [by Hale]. Included in The Best Short Stories, 1942. New York: Council on Books in Wartime, 1943. *.
A86 "Overnight." Collier's. 11 Jan. 1941: 33, 34, 43, 44.
A87 "Book Review." Harper's Bazaar. 1 Mar. 1941: 77, 106, 108.
A88 "The Haircut." Ladies Home Journal. 58.4. Apr. 1941: *.
A89 "The Marching Feet." The New Yorker. 14 June 1941: 25-26. Included in Between the Dark and the Daylight [by Hale].
A90 "Cab-Taxi." The New Yorker. 4 Oct. 1941: 36, 38-39. Included in Between the Dark and the Daylight [by Hale]. Included in A New England Girlhood [by Hale].
A91 "Gone Are the Days." The New Yorker. 15 Nov. 1941: 23-25. Included in Between the Dark and the Daylight [by Hale].
A92 "Sunday-1913." Harper's Bazaar. 1942: *. Included in Between the Dark and the Daylight [by Hale]. Included in O. Henry Memorial Award Prize Stories of 1942. Ed. Herschel Brickell. Garden City, New York: Country Life P, 171-191.
A93 "Portrait of an American." Readers' Digest. Apr. 1942: *. + +
A94 "Sailor Named Bill." Woman's Home Companion. July 1942: *. + +
A95 "The Fair." The New Yorker. 1 Aug. 1942: 15-19. Included in Between the Dark and the Daylight [by Hale]. Included in A New England Girlhood [by Hale]. Included in Secrets [by Hale].
A96 "Georgetown Nights." The New Yorker. 19 Sept. 1942: 15-18. Included in Between the Dark and the Daylight [by Hale].
A97 "The Japanese Garden" The New Yorker. 28 Nov. 1942: 19-22. Included in Between the Dark and the Daylight [by Hale]. A98 "New England in Her Bones." Mademoiselle. Dec. 1942: *.
A99 "Who Lived and Died Believing." Harper's Bazaar. 1943: *. Included in Between the Dark and the Daylight [by Hale]. Included in Fifty Best American Short Stories 1915-1965. Boston: Houghton Mifflin, 1965. 286-304. Included in O. Henry Memorial Award Prize Stories of 1943. Ed. Herschel Brickell. New York: Doubleday, 1943. 181-200. Included in O. Henry Memorial Prize Stories. Garden City: Doubleday. 179-200.
A100 "The Season of Summer." Harper's Bazaar:*. Included in It's a Woman's World: A Collection of Stories from Harper's Bazaar. Ed. Mary Louise White Aswell. New York, London: Whittlesey House, McGraw-Hill, 1944. * A101 "Some Day I'll Find You." Good Housekeeping. Sept. 1945: *. Included in The Empress's Ring [by Hale].
A102 "No Other Gods." The New Yorker. 1 Sept. 1945: 23-24. Included in The Pattern of Perfection [by Hale].
A103 "The Way They Wanted Her To Be." Good Housekeeping. May 1946: *. + +
A104 "A Fine and Private Place." Today's Woman. June 1946: *. Included in The Earliest Dreams [by Hale]. A105 "Entrance Into Life." The New Yorker. 14 June 1947: 22-23. Included in The Pattern of Perfection [by Hale]. A106 "The Fox." Today's Woman. Jan. 1950: *. Included in The Empress's Ring [by Hale].
A107 "The Snows of Childhood." The New Yorker. 17 Mar. 1951: 29-33. Included in The Empress's Ring [by Hale].
A108 "Brahmin Beachhead." Town & Country. June 1951: 32, 86-89, 94-96.
A109 "On the Beach." Virginia Quarterly Review. July 1952: *. Included in The Empress's Ring [by Hale].
A110 "One Good Dress." Ladies Home Journal. Aug. 1952: *. + + [publishing information] A111 "Inside." The New Yorker. 12 Dec. 1953: 95-97. Included in The Empress's Ring [by Hale].
A112 "The Empress's Ring." The New Yorker. 10 Apr. 1954: 35-37. Included in A New England Girlhood [by Hale].
A113 "The Bubble" The New Yorker. 24 July 1954: 20-24. Included in The Empress's Ring [by Hale]. Included in Stories from the New Yorker: 1950-1960. New York: Simon & Schuster, 1960. *. Included in A Woman's Place: An Anthology of Short Stories. Ed. L.M. Schulman. New York: MacMillan, 1974. 196-209.
A114 "Object of Virtue." The New Yorker. 4 Sept. 1954: 22-23. Included in The Empress's Ring [by Hale]. Included in Broadcast Stories. Stockholm: Sveriges Radio, 1960. 96-102.
A115 "Miss August." The New Yorker. 18 Sept. 1954: 38-44. Included in The Empress's Ring [by Hale]. Included in Heaven and Hardpan Farm [by Hale].
A116 "The Secret Garden." The New Yorker. 2 Oct. 1954: 28-29. Included in The Empress's Ring [by Hale].
A117 "The Readville Stars." The New Yorker. 23 Oct. 1954: 41-42. Included in The Empress's Ring [by Hale]. Included in A New England Girlhood [by Hale].
A118 "The Copley Plaza." The New Yorker. 13 Nov. 1954: 42-45. Included in The Empress's Ring [by Hale]. Included in A New England Girlhood [by Hale]. Included in City Life. Eds. Oscar Schoenfeld and Helene MacLean. New York: Grossman, 1969. *.
A119 "The New Order." The New Yorker. 27 Nov. 1954: 39-40. Included in The Empress's Ring [by Hale].
A120 "The Good Things of Life." The New Yorker. 11 Dec. 1954: 34- 39. Pseudonym Lee Alderman.
A121 "The Place and the Time." The New Yorker. 1 Jan. 1955: 17-18. Included in The Empress's Ring [by Hale].
A122 "The First Day of School." The New Yorker. 19 Feb. 1955: 32-35. Included in The Empress's Ring [by Hale].
A123 "Charlotte Russe." The New Yorker. 9 Apr. 1955: 29-30. Included in The Empress's Ring. Included in A New England Girlhood [by Hale].
A124 "Nothing Good or Bad." The New Yorker. 9 July 1955: 20-23.
A125 "The Coasts of New England." The New Yorker. 10 Sept. 1955: 37-42.
A126 "Pierce's." The New Yorker. 19 Nov. 1955: 46-69. Included in A New England Girlhood [by Hale].
A127 "The Dances." The New Yorker. 10 Dec. 1955: 46-48.
A128 "The Pattern of Perfection." The New Yorker. 24 Dec. 1955: 16-22. Included in The Pattern of Perfection [by Hale] A129 "The Object." The New Yorker. 17 Mar. 1956: 46-75. Included in Heaven and Hardpan Farm [by Hale].
A130 "Ever Let the Fancy." The New Yorker. 31 Mar. 1956: 35-38.
A131 "The Narrow Sense of the Word." The New Yorker. 28 Apr. 1956: 43-46.
A132 "The Other Road." Folio. Spring 1956: *.
A133 "A Summer's Long Dream" The New Yorker. 14 July 1956: 22-28. Included in The Pattern of Perfection. Included in The Best American Short Stories 1957. Ed. Martha Foley. Boston: Houghton Mifflin, 1957. 155-170.
A134 "The Model." The New Yorker. 4 Aug. 1956: 30-57. Included in Heaven and Hardpan Farm [by Hale].
A135 "The Picture." The New Yorker. 1 Sept. 1956: 24-36. Included in Heaven and Hardpan Farm [by Hale].
A136 "Outside." The New Yorker. 29 Sept. 1956: 29-33. Included in The Pattern of Perfection [by Hale].
A137 "The Beam." The New Yorker. 27 Oct. 1956: 32-40. Included in Heaven and Hardpan Farm [by Hale].
A138 "The Barn." The New Yorker. 22 Dec. 1956: 22-30. Included in Heaven and Hardpan Farm [by Hale].
A139 "How to Choose Your Memories." Vogue. 1 Jan. 1957: *. A140 "An Introduction to Glamour." The New Yorker. 2 Mar. 1957: 28-31.
A141 "The King of Fancy's Daughter." The New Yorker. 27 Apr. 1957: 28-33. Included in The Pattern of Perfection [by Hale].
A142 "The Secret Secret." The New Yorker. 31 Aug. 1957: 30-33. Included in A New England Girlhood [by Hale]. Included in Secrets [by Hale].
A143 "A Haunting." The New Yorker. 26 Oct. 1957: 44-48. Included in The Pattern of Perfection [by Hale].
A144 "There Is a Host Approaching Nigh." The New Yorker. 30 Nov. 1957: 52-56. Included in The Life in the Studio [by Hale].
A145 "A Slow Boat to China," Virginia Quarterly Review. 1958: *. Included in The Pattern of Perfection [by Hale]. Included in Prize Stories 1958: The O.Henry Awards. New York: Doubleday, 1958. 167-177.
A146 "What God Was Writing." Texas Quarterly. 1958: 35-40.
A147 "Coming Out." The New Yorker. 4 Jan. 1958: 18-21. Included in A New England Girlhood [by Hale]. Included in Secrets [by Hale].
A148 "Child Training at Harvard." The New Yorker. 15 Feb. 1958: 28-30.
A149 "A New Place." The New Yorker. 3 May 1958: 41-58. Included in The Pattern of Perfection [by Hale].
A150 "Through the Looking Glass to Reality." Saturday Review. 8 Nov. 1958: 10-12, 39-40.
A151 "A Curious Lapse." The New Yorker. 1 August 1959: 24-30. Included in The Pattern of Perfection [by Hale].
A152 "Flotsam." The New Yorker. 5 Sept. 1959: 32-38. Included in The Pattern of Perfection [by Hale].
A153 "Fists Across the Sea." The New Yorker. 16 Jan. 1960: 36-38.
A154 "Rich People." The New Yorker. 9 July 1960: 32-54. Included in The Pattern of Perfection [by Hale].
A155 "The Poor Man's War Between the States." The New Yorker. 25 March 1961: 34-37.
A156 "The Magic of Creativity." Saturday Evening Post. 29 April 1961: *. + +
A157 "Handful of R's." Vogue. 1 November 1961: 111.
A158 "A Gift from the Shops." The New Yorker. 11 November 1961: 48-51.
A159 "Hemingway and the Courage to Be." Virginia Quarterly Review. 1962: 620-639.
A160 "What, This Old Thing?" Authors Guild Bulletin. 1962: *. + +
A161 "How to Keep from Writing." Saturday Review. 7 April 1962: *. + +
A162 "Handsome, Alert, a Real Young Blade." Vogue. May 1962: 152-153.
A163 "Mrs. Harcourt's Mare." The New Yorker. 28 July 1962: 20-23. Included in The Life in the Studio [by Hale].
A164 "The Feel of Writing." Saturday Review. 8 September 1962: 16-18.
A165 "In a Word." The New Yorker. 27 July 1963: 80-83.
A166 "Colonel Sartoris and Mr. Snopes." Vogue. 1 August 1963: 112-113, 135-136, 138-139. Included in Conversations with William Faulkner. Ed. M. Thomas Inge. Jackson,MS: UP of Mississippi, 1999. 227.
A167 "Girl with the Goat-Cart." The New Yorker. 30 November 1963: 55-56. Included in The Life in the Studio [by Hale].
A168 "An Age for Action." Ladies' Home Journal. March 1965: 92-93.
A169 "My Mother's Solitudes." The New Yorker. 6 March 1965. 38-42. Included in The Life in the Studio [by Hale].
A170 "Sunday Lunch." The New Yorker. 8 May 1965: 44-49. Included in Prize Stories 1966: The O.Henry Awards. Eds. Richard Poirier and William Abrahams. Garden City, NY: Doubleday, 1966. 161-170.
A171 "A Fiction Writer Faces Facts." Saturday Review (Washington, D.C.) 12 June 1965: 23-5, 80-81.
A172 "The Signorina." Transatlanic Review. Autumn 1965: 44-51.
A173 "New England." Venture. October 1965: *. + +
A174 "Eyes and No Eyes; or, the Art of Seeing." The New Yorker. 20 November 1965: 52-59. Included in The Life in the Studio [by Hale].
A175 "Notes While Trying to Get to Work." Authors Guild Bulletin. 1966: *. + +
A176 "All Anybody." Georgia Review. Spring 1966: *.
A177 "Family Ties." Southern Review. Spring 1966. *. + + [publication information]
A178 "Animals in the House." Harper's Magazine. September 1966: 94-100.
A179 "The Most Elegant Drawing Room in Europe." The New Yorker. 17 September 1966: 55-64. Included in Fifty Years of the American Short Story: From the O.Henry Awards 1919-1969. Ed. William Miller Abrahams. Garden City: Doubleday, 1970. *.
A180 "Waiting." Virginia Quarterly Review. Autumn 1966: 574-586.
A181 "Journeys." Virginia Quarterly Review. 1967. *. + + [date only] Included in The Life in the Studio [by Hale].
A182 "The Innocent." Virginia Quarterly Review. Spring 1967: 281-296.
A183 "What Haunts Thee in Fond Shapes." The New Yorker. 5 August 1967: 27-29. Included in The Life in the Studio [by Hale].
A184 "How to Take Criticism." Saturday Review. c. 1968. *. + +
A185 "The World, the Flesh, and the Devil." The New Yorker. 27 April 1968: 38-42. Included in The Life in the Studio [by Hale].
A186 "Inheriting a Garden." The New Yorker. 18 May 1968: 112-122. Included in The Life in the Studio [by Hale].
A187 "An Arrangement in Parents." The New Yorker. 22 June 1968: 27-31. Included in The Life in the Studio [by Hale].
A188 "A Good Light." The New Yorker. 28 September 1968: 100-120. Included in The Life in the Studio [by Hale].
A189 "Joyous Gard." The New Yorker. 12 October 1968: 175-190. Included in The Life in the Studio [by Hale].
A190 "The Other Side." The New Yorker. 1 March 1969: 82-93. Included in The Life in the Studio [by Hale].
A191 "Mr. Hamilton." Michigan Quarterly Review. Spring 1970: 105-113.
A192 "Dreams of Rich People." McCall's. August 1972: 86-87, 123-126.
A193 "Half-Glimpses of Genius." Virginia Quarterly Review. 1973: 309-312.
A194 "A Ceremony of Innocence." Virginia Quarterly Review. Summer 1976: 389-399.
A195 "The Real Thing." Virginia Quarterly Review. Spring 1979: 275-283.
A196 "The Interior." Virginia Quarterly Review. Spring 1980: 297-306.
A197 "Tastes." Virginia Quarterly Review. Autumn 1982: 594-599.
A198 "A Part." Virginia Quarterly Review. Winter 1985: 76-78. Included in "Eric Clapton's Lover" and Other Stories from theVirginia Quarterly Review. Eds. Sheila McMillen and George Garrett. Charlottesville, VA: UP of Virginia, 1990. 100-102.
A199 "The Toimi." The Virginia Quarterly Review. Spring 1989: 231-234.
A200 "My Mother's Clothes." Ladies Home Journal. *. Included in The Life in the Studio as "The Black Cape" [by Hale].
A201 "All He Ever Wanted." Redbook. *: 28-29, 70-76.
A202 "Always Afternoon." *.
A203 "China Sets." Redbook. *.
A204 "Christmas in the South." Redbook. *.
A205 "Crimson Autumn." *.
A206 "Earth Reborn." Redbook. *. A207 "Fear." *.
A208 "The Last Time." *.
A209 "The Lost Love." *.
A210 "Odd Fellow's Hall." Scribner's. *.
A211 "She Never Saw the Circus." *.
A212 "The Stranger Venus." Redbook. *.
7. Periodical Publication of Poems:
A213 "Character." Scribner's. January 1930. *. + +
A214 "Private Freedom." Good Housekeeping. November 1946. *. + +
A215 "Chiaroscuro." Saturday Review of Literature. 16 December 1950. *. + +
A216 "Holiday." Ladies Home Journal. July 1951. *. + +
A217 "Stick and Stone." *.
A218 "Writer: Virginia." Ladies Home Journal. December 1941. *. + +
8. Selected Reviews by Hale:
A219 "A Passage to Relationship." Antioch Review. 1960: 19-30.
A220 "Sweetly Sings the Donkey." Cosmopolitan. August, 1963: 24.
A221 "The Old Breed." New York Times Book Review. 31 Oct. 1965.
A222 "Recollections of Virginia Woolf." Virginia Quarterly Review. 39. 1973: 309-312
A222 "Virginia Woolf: a Biography. Virginia Quarterly Review. 49. 1973: 309-312.
A223 "The Woman Said Yes: Encounters with Life and Death. New York Times Book Review. 2 May 1976: 4.
A224 "Women's Insights." New York Times Book Review. 16 Dec. 1979. *
A225 "Cassatt and Her Circle." Archives of American Art Journal. 24. 3. 1984: 24-25.
9. Other Published Works:
A226 "Nathan Hale." Defense Series Pamphlet. 1941. + +
A227 "Words of Nathan Hale Recalled in Heroism of Today." The Sunday Star [Washington, D.C.] 29 March 1942: B-4.
A228 "Nathan Hale." There Were Giants in the Land. New York: Farrar & Rinehart, 1942. 48-55.
A229 "The Question Is: To Be Or Not To Be--a Snob!" Chicago Sunday Tribune. 24 Dec. 1950. Part 4, Page 8.
A230 "Lying Fallow." Writer. 1945. Speech given at Bread Loaf.
A230 "Letter to a Young Writer: Faith Is the Keynote to a Really Successful Novel: Author Nancy Hale Defines the Necessary Ingredients for a Story That Will Succeed." Richmond Times Dispatch, 29 November 1953. 13.
A231 "Boston." [Letter to Department of Explication] The New Yorker. 13 October 1956: 124-132.
A232 Introduction. The Complete Peterkin Papers. By Lucretia P. Hale. Boston: Houghton Mifflin: 1960.
A233 "The Two-Way Imagination." Adventures of the Mind. Ed. Richard Thruelsen. New York: Knopf, 1961.